# Lungelo Msibi

# Information Technology Professional

Ncabaneni, Mankayane madjr50@gmail.com (+268) 76186226

I am a very versatile Information Technology professional who has been in data communication and networking long enough to have database development steal his heart. Currently fascinated and learning about Data Science topics spanning from Business Intelligence to Artificial Intelligence.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

# Work Experience

### **IT Support Engineer**

Netcomm Swaziland - Matsapha July 2018 to December 2018

- Installing and configuring computer hardware operating systems and applications.
- Monitoring and maintaining computer systems and networks.
- Troubleshooting system and network problems, diagnosing and solving hardware or software faults
- Repairing and replacing parts as required.
- Setting up new users' accounts and profiles and deal with password issues.
- Conducting electrical safety checks on computer equipment.
- Prioritizing and managing several open issues at one time.

#### **Network Engineer**

Ludvondvolo Wireless Internet Service Provider (LWISP) - Mankayane January 2016 to June 2018

#### **Trainer & Presenter**

Green World - Manzini January 2014 to June 2015

### **Related Skills**

- I can implement Data Warehouses through Microsoft Visual Studio's Integration Services (SSIS): Extract-Transform-Load (ETL).
- A frequent user of Stored Procedures and User-defined Functions to solve regularly used queries (TSQL). Actually S-Procs and UDFs are my favorite tools in Database Development.
- Quite familiar and I have regularly used these technologies too: MS Office (Excel, Access, Word), PHP (phpMyAdmin), SPSS, both JSON and XML for encoding data from databases into flat or raw files.
- Highly disciplined professional of sober habits that observes corporate etiquette and a desire to learn both in formal and informal settings.
- I can implement Data Warehouses through Microsoft Visual Studio's Integration Services (SSIS).
- Easy person to communicate with I am very trainable actually and amazing interpersonal skills as well as excellent documentation skills for future use/reference and reporting.
- I am a great problem solver and fast thinker with huge passion for technology. I breath technology.

- A continual academic currently absorbing (plus entry level experience) of tools and languages used for data analysis R, Excel, SQL, Python & Tableau.
- I find refuge in MS Excel to demonstrate and implement Data Cleansing, Data Visualization, Reporting, Pivoting Tables and even Dashboards.
- Knowledgeable in extracting and pre-processing data for analysis in OLAP Data Warehouses.
- Sharp statistical analysis practices as well as predictive analysis drawn from data sources and data patterns.
- Good programming skills in C++, Java, C# including web development languages: JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, HMTL5.
- I have designed and developed databases that help monitor municipal councils' properties they oversee, creating efficiency for the administration department.

# Education

### Post Graduate Diploma in Data Science in Data Science

Institute of Business Management (IIBM)
July 2018 to August 2019

# **Bachelor's in Software Engineering with Multimedia**

Limkokwing University - Gaborone, BW July 2008 to December 2015

#### O' Level

Ka-Boyce High School January 2005 to November 2006

# **Certificate in Junior Certificate**

Ka-Boyce High School January 2002 to November 2004

### Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lungelo-msibi-00b65615

#### Awards

### **International Leadership Academy Alumni**

July 2005

### **Best African Short Story Writer**

August 2013

### Certifications/Licenses

### CompTIA A+

June 2017 to June 2020

### **MTA SQL Database Fundamentals 2016**

October 2017 to Present

### CompTIA Network+

November 2017 to November 2020

### MCSA SQL Database Development 2016

March 2018 to Present

### Assessments

Indeed Assessments are tests that job seekers can use to demonstrate their knowledge and abilities.

# Technical Support Skills — Highly Proficient

Feb 2019

View my full results at: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share\_assignment/efhjlymkc1i-8sgy

# **Verbal Communication — Highly Proficient**

Feb 2019

View my full results at: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share\_assignment/urhezrg5ufzyevgh

#### **Written Communication — Proficient**

Feb 2019

View my full results at: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share\_assignment/knc2mvehpbnge-lq

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.